lecture, you don't need to leave, just come in once
.  So when
we were planning this retreat, Tim and I were thinking about what
classes to
teach.  And it is bad manners in Buddhism
not to finish the teachings.
As the last lamri, we taught for 12 years
and we completed it.  You should
applaud yourself.
Yes. And
there is another very important teaching,
which is called Tanzin.  Tandin.
Tanzin
means our habit of thinking that the pen
comes from itself, of clinging to the
pen and thinking that it comes from
itself, not from
us.  And when you believe that the pen
was made in a factory and you have a
disease, it is called danzin.   We
all have it.  We all have this disease
.  It's
funny, but it's a very, very old disease.
Shanden
means it is a dispute between two people.
We have a special thing, when you arrive
you start to see some kind of
dispute on the road.  It's like two
drivers arguing with each other and they
get out of the car and start
swearing.  And our friend who bumped into someone
in Arizona and he started
arguing about something, then the other guy pointed his
finger at him and he was like, "Okay, okay, I won't
argue."  So
we call it a shandem in the Ube language.  This is a
struggle, some kind of argument.
And in this
book, and it's a very long book of poetry, it's
called
Struggle with the Good Side of the Mind and the
Bad Side of the Mind.  This is such a
bitter struggle, you know
.  And my teacher introduced me to
this teaching many years ago, probably about
35 or 40 years ago.
And he laid it out for us, and it's
quite long.  And he didn't have time
to finish.  And he died before he, well,
finished teaching.  And it is very
bad manners not to finish teaching the
doctrine.  And I realized that I would like to
teach these teachings to you and finish
them.  And this is an incredible lily, an extremely
incredible book.  The struggle is in your
mind and it is unraveling.  Your mind
seems to split into two parts:
good and bad.  Angel and devil.  And they
argue among themselves.  An incredible
conversation between them.  And when this happens
in our corner of the mind
all the time
and you remember it, you say, do you remember the pen?
Yes.  Yes, I remember the pen, but
we are constantly saying it all alone, well, constantly in
our minds.  And I
do that too.  I'm sitting in my
house, I'm
cold [music].  What's the coolest thing you
could do for a llama?  Plant them in
Kyoto.  All the toilets there
are heated, it's warm there.
And I imagine myself in the revue, when
I sit in this toilet, I'm
warm and when in Almaznaya Gora I
go outside, to the toilet and it's so
cold there and I feel this cold.  And
even at this moment, I have
this debate going on in my
mind.  This is a very, very beautiful book that
we are studying, that we have started, that we are
starting a topic on.
We started 14 years ago, in
2010. It won't take me long to
explain this.
I refuse to refuse to teach you
this.  And if you have taught
students the secret teachings, if you are a person of the
diamond path, then
perhaps Buddha has sent this book just for you right
now.  And
you could say yes, of course,
or no.  It is possible that your path, the
diamond
path, is connected to this book, is
connecting.  Perhaps this book will help
you on your diamond path.  This is how I
see it, I'm not done.   It will take
us 3-4 years to
complete these teachings.  I want to
finish them.  And it wasn't before this.
I would really like to make
these teachings available to people all over the world.  And
when I teach, I understand much better while
teaching.  By teaching, I
understand better myself.  And you will all be teachers too,
if you want to teach well.
Try practicing on your sister,
brother.  How old is she?  19.
Wow.  He will be a DCI teacher next
year.  Yes.  Gshe is talking to someone in the
audience.
I think Buddha sent you this book and
you should finish it with
me.  I include this in our Diamond
Path course.  It's basically
[music] the
argument for the meaning of emptiness.  This is a unique
book because it is
funny.  It is written in such a way that it
is funny.
And sometimes you laugh, even if you
don't understand anything, like,
"Ha-ha-ha."  Yes, it's really funny.  This is
true.  This is
self-criticism.
Self-criticism is probably useful.  Before I sit down to
teach, this is who I blame.
Let Aha.  They do it on a warm
morning.  Why is it so
cold now?  Well, that is, there is no
difference.  You are constantly complaining about something, about
someone or about something in your mind.
And in this case, this devil who speaks
and
complains and that's why I worked on this
text.  Have you heard of the idea of ​​five houses?
What's happening to Isaiah?
What I
think is one of the
oldest organizations that exists in our country,
if I'm not mistaken,
it was founded in 1993, 32 years ago.  And
she kept growing and growing.  Then it
started, then DCI started
and
other dips.  He has been
joking for almost 40 years and it has become a very
large organization.
If you take 18
courses, fundamentally 18 courses, it will
take you six or seven years.  But
if you continue the diamond
courses, it's six and another six-seven years.  And
then it
goes out and then some more meditation to work.
That's another 5 years.  In total, it
turns out to be about 19 years.  Then you have someone to teach.
You have to do all this before you
die.  And you too, there's too much of everything here
.  And what were we thinking?  We would like
you all to become
teachers.  We really want you all to
teach.  If you are so stubborn that you
come to the desert and attend these
teachings, then most likely you will be a
teacher.  And to be a teacher,
it's very
similar to how you teach in Diamond
Mountain.  We have a lot of problems and we
thought that the people who come to these
teachings would teach the Diamond
Way from here.  And this is an incredible path.  It is my
dream that you become teachers.   There are
so many things to learn.  In fact,
you can study for 40 years and
then become a teacher and you won't have any
hair left.  You see.  So you
have to specialize in something.  It's like
you go to university.  You get,
ah, for example, uh, a degree in
English or science from
Columbia University or
other universities.  Our idea is that
you will choose a specialization
and we invite you to all classes.
Maybe you can look into the middle of
your heart and you have five
characteristics, five choices.  You can
do your PhD and then
teach in one of these
houses.  It's like in universities like
Princeton.
You have to join a
house and you have friends there, you have
support, you
study together and
you are in your own home.  And
we also wanted to build five houses here.
And you have to make a choice,
choose.  And the first is to choose a
teacher.  Remember the first act of the
classic?  Yes.
Indeed, you can choose the traditional
classic home ACI
path 18 + 18 36
courses.  This is
basically this Geshe house.
If you've completed 18 basic
courses, you've completed the
basic important Geshe courses, by the way,
they're
not, uh, you know, sitting in breaks
and not even knowing when the next
class is.  And they tell you, "Oh, we didn't have
class."  They don't talk, they don't
study, just like we don't study in universities
.  This is some kind of very crazy
system.  You will
graduate, someone will graduate with philosophy,
someone with
something else.  And some people are very studious and
love studying philosophy.  Me too, I
like talking about
philosophy.  And that's exactly how I learned things
.  And I, if I wanted to walk this
path, if I wanted to become a Buddha, then I would
choose this path of the philosopher.  The second is the
home of semathi, which is
meditation.  We say, "I'm studying this book."
This
book, the last 35 books
weren't enough.  And then you ask, can I
meditate?  I don't want to read books
all day.  And
many choose meditation and
their dream is to be a meditation teacher, a
Tibetan teacher.  And that's wonderful.
And we should have a DM that is
dedicated specifically to meditation - it is a
privilege and a
pleasure to join
Mutsamat,
meditation.  You will probably look something like this
in the pictures.  By the way, great
meditators, as we
call them, they don't shine.
John Brady, one of the best meditators
I
know.  He doesn't, he doesn't glow.  It doesn't
look like this on this
slide.  I mean, it's
such a
simple idea.  You can look like
a businessman and when you're involved in
import, export, or some kind of
corporate
activity, you're in charge of something there
.  It all depends on
you.  If you are
really really involved in meditation,
you have an interest.  And when you see your
future, when you close your eyes and you
imagine that you see yourself
teaching meditation to a group of people, and we
invite you into this house.  This doesn't mean
you can't study philosophy, but it's
just what you
specialize in.  When you decide who I am
.  That's what I tell people on the plane.
You sit next to someone on a plane, you
don't know them, and you ask them, "What do you
do for a living?"  If you say,
"Hey, I'm a
meditation teacher," then you should come to
this house
100%.  If you study philosophy, then
you should join the ACI house, classically the
house of classics.  So the third house,
what do we call it?
House on the mountain.  I really
enjoy going on
retreats.  And that's it.  They are always
missing something.  They always want to go
on retreats,
retreats.  And I would like to teach you
this book.  No, no, sorry, I'm
busy here.  No, I can't read the book.   The
only thing they want is to be somewhere on a
mountain and in retreat, independent, in
deep
retreat, not meeting people,
maybe once every six
years.  And so, if you are the kind of
person who
dreams of constantly spending time in
retreats, then you can join
this house, home.
I'm not
sure
how to
choose people.  I don't know which house will be
the most popular, but I'm sure
if at least five people are in each
house, that's enough to start.   It
doesn't matter whether there are 100
people in a classic house or two people in a
house for reddit people.  It doesn't matter.  I want
you to choose the place where you want to
be.  So, what's the
fourth one?
Yes, the home of the
lamrim.  As you have seen over the last 12 years,
lamrim is a big topic.  We call this the
great theme of lamrim.
After John has completed several hundred
lamrims, you can dedicate your entire
life to it.  And there are a lot of
beautiful ones, like the one we finished, the
12-year-old Lamrim Chenmo, we taught, we
taught for 12 years.  And you can
become a lamrim master.  And this is it, this is
very sweet and incredibly beautiful.
Maybe this is what you want.  And, of course
, everyone wants to be in the fifth house of
diamonds
, because that's where everyone wants to be.  I won't
lie to you.  I'm not, I'm not forbidding you from
being there.  And I, on the other hand, forbid you from
being there, because you will ignore the
next other houses.  So our plan is for
you to join the first four.  Don't
decide this today.  This doesn't mean
you have to sign a contract today.
But choose what you are most
attracted to.
My my my teacher gave me advice on
all five topics Geshe is what you don't
hate the most.  What is this 13th
year?  Why is this an unlucky number?  I
hate logic.  Then you will become a
master.
His advice was: "Join a house that
you don't
like, because that's what you're
not very good at. And when you balance
your life, when you become a master of what
you're not interested in, then you
start to be a master of everything."  That is,
you balance, you
learn to do redrits, study
philosophy.  There is also such
an option.  And I'm not pushing you there, if
you've been sitting, thinking and dreaming about your own
little cottage or chalet in the mountains, you
can join this house
because you want to choose.  You are free to
choose.  And what I'm asking you this
week is, imagine that you're already in
one of these houses and feel what it's like to be in
it.  And I said, and you can't
repeat that to your wife.  I asked her to
go to the store and buy jeans.
And
there we went into a store where there's no seating
for men, and she's trying on these 42
pairs of jeans.  And how much did she end up
buying?  She didn't buy
any,
zero.  I'm saying what it means.  Try
many homes.  Try it.  We are not
pushing you, we are not forcing you to do this
today.
What a cool thing I did on my
tour, on the last tour I went on.
Stanley
knows.  I was very brave and bought her
jeans.  And they approached her.   Can
you imagine?  After I die, I
will write my life story.
It should start with the phrase that he
bought his wife
jeans at home.  Yes, they are like in Harry
Potter.  How they decided which house
they belong to, which house they belong to, how
they belong.  Ask
the audience what it's
called.
Sorting sorting hat.
We didn't choose this hat.  You
put on this hat and it talks to you
.  We didn't have
such a hat, so you'll have to decide
that for
yourself.  And
who didn't want some Harry Potter in
Slytherin?
So
now this week's crayfish
you buy when Aha.  When Tim
tells you, you have to choose the house you
want to
be in.  This means what you wanted to
teach, what you would like to teach people.
And you will focus on that.  And we will
help you
focus, and we will help you become a
specialist, a doctor in this
area.
Well, that doesn't mean other people can't
come.  We will specially create courses so that
you can
become the coolest teacher in this house.
After
that, you will set out certain requirements.  Then you
can join the diamond house.
So your home, one of the four, is your
path to becoming a diamond home.
So we ask you to choose one
of these houses that will lead you to the
diamond house.  Such a
system.
Good.  This will be a
super home for those who will be super classy
in their own home.
Think about what you would like to teach.
Visualize, imagine that you are
a teacher.  What is the
most important teaching in the Diamond Way?
You can imagine when you become a Buddha.
You can imagine yourself meditating.
Imagine yourself building.  Why did you teach
people that when John and I are together, we will have a
lot of hair, a lot of
hair, and my belly will
go away.  And one of the diamond paths, and
diamond exercises, is to visualize yourself
as who you want to become.  And sometimes you
will do that.  And now we'll
talk about it.
Now a book
called The Debate of Ayangola and the
Devil.  We will make the
roof.  This is a fact that I use.  I
take a book like this, which was in the
last class, which book
was translated by Gypsum.  It's on my
computer, I'm opening it.
I insert a photo there and I
teach with this photo what I
did in the last lesson.  And
I don't have a picture of the debate between the angel and the devil.
Why?  Because you will make this picture in
every
house, every house will make a
picture that will teach this part of
this book.
I will teach you today one of
these
verses of the debate between angels and the
devil.  It so happens
that a bad
friend was not
very polite
to a good friend.  I would really like
each of them, well, to guide you
in this, to sit together and you would
compose
idioms.  You will draw these idioms as you
teach it.  Therefore, we will have a special
lesson, which will be divided into four
parts.  Every day the house will rise and
say: "Here is our picture for the first
verse."
And this is how we taught from our home.
This is the first verse of the best of our home,
our
best.  You need to
be like Harry
Potter.  He even reads books even
when he
walks.  We actually have snakes here when
you walk, so be careful.
So, I had a
contract with a
photo agency before.  I bought
photos from them.  I did this for several years
, paying for
photos.  Instead of looking it up
on the internet, I had a contract and
bought photos from them
.
And now we have artificial intelligence that is
getting better and better.  And you can
make these pictures using
artificial
intelligence.  You will write some kind of
promo, you will write a text,
for example, a person throws a handful of spaghetti on the
head of a person who is meditating.  You tell
him to do it and he will do it.
He's having a laugh because artificial
intelligence doesn't always listen to him.  By
the way, your
future will most likely include a video of you with real
intelligence.  I think intelligence is cool.
You can use it, you
can create a picture.  And it's a cool
tool.
And the audience finds it interesting and artificial intelligence
entertains the audience.  And
then it's an incredible tool to
ask your
students, what is this picture?  What does
this picture mean?  Your picture should have
power, a strong story, and tell
a story.  It's much easier
to remember philosophy through a picture.
So we will tell stories with
pictures.  I don't choose these pictures.  I
want four pictures for each of the
houses.  And I want to see what your house
will do.  Then I and I will decide which of
us will be better.
We will give you the gold of the golden
hat.  Oh, okay.  This is very, very
American.  And we will
enjoy the meantime.  A
very famous friend of ours from Mexico
who has a funny
show.  No, no, he has a
show.
Well, we had a context about idioms.
So show it.  He did his best, by the way
.  He won a prize.  And it was
incredible.  Geshe Michael talks about Juan,
who hosts the show Peach
Tree.  By the way, he just got back from
Kyoto.  You have to make
him mad.  He and Adam, they gave knowledge.
And it was an incredible course they taught in Kyoto
.  And thank you to our Japanese
friends who helped them there.
Juan and Adamndrade taught very interesting
classes, and they received a grant from
Sim to fly to Quito and teach.
By chance, the plane itself stopped in
Hawaii and Juan went to Huahu.  This place is in
Hawaii.  This is in eastern Hawaii.
He said that in the north he said that
he
went surfing there and that was what the
northern beach was like
.  Well, there's Huacu
and a and this beach.  There are a lot of
beautiful women in bikinis.
I don't know which of these beaches you
were from.  But if you
want
something, if you want to get a
grant, you have to submit documents.  And they
flew to Coyote and helped a lot of
people and taught a very
incredible
course.  Anyone can
do it.  And everyone can do it.  This is
what Jepubs box is called.  So
today I'm going to be teaching the angel and
devil debate, and as I explain it to you, think
about the image you want to create
of your home.  This will help you
learn.  Pictures also hold
people.  They help keep you from falling
asleep.  They help
remember things and aid
in understanding and
representation.
And you can
learn, you can become a good
teacher.  This is your responsibility.
Each of you is
different.  Adam is not here.
His first lesson.  Can I
show it?
This was about 12 years ago in
Phoenix.  I was
coaching him on what to say, and he just stood there like that
.  He just froze on stage.  And he's
like: "And I say:
'Adam, ah, and I say: 'Adam, sit down.'"  And he
sat down.  And I realized, "Okay, let's
work on this."
completely frozen frozen
Even me, when I first went on stage, I was
like, well, it was something similar.  My teacher
told me, "Sit down,
shut up."  And you will learn from this my
understanding.  Each of you will learn this.
Each of you, you can be a teacher and
you should be a teacher.  And in the tradition of
ancient books, you can't take classes.
Attend class if you have no
intention of becoming a
teacher.  This is our old tradition.  You
cannot attend classes if you
do not intend to pass on these
teachings.  Sometimes I ask, "Are you listening?
If you have a really good meal, I'll
listen to you. So let's start.
The devil
talks,
and the bad part says that you have to
lead a person to
something, when you don't think about
anything.
Whenever you
meditate, your meditation should be
so diffused, diffused.
Sit down, relax, don't think about
anything. Just say to yourself, "Om!" Who will
talk? Who will talk now?
Yes, it's the devil. You see, this is my
meditation system. You laugh. A long time ago
, when I met my
first Yoga teacher, I said,
"Listen, I don't know if I can
do this or not.  Well, the truth is, I don't know if
I can do it.  I travel
a lot." And she
told me, "We have a tip that when you
arrive at a hotel, wherever you
arrive, whatever country you are in,
find a yoga studio."
There's a really cool
story in Chinese. I arrived in China
and there was a class in Chinese
for pregnant women. I didn't understand what they were
saying. And I got there,
all the women were pregnant. I got the
coolest stretch of my life there. So
I would like to
tell you that I traveled to all the
countries. I looked for yoga studios and went
there. And I
heard
100 terrible
meditations. Don't even think about
anything.
Relax, let go of your thoughts. And I'm
like okay. And
then unexpectedly, by chance,
I thought that as a
magician, people are being taught the wrong meditations. I
was
shocked. I thought that there were few people who
teach meditation correctly. And this has been
going on for 400 years. And this teacher
Yoshi  Genyenze, this writer, this is the
man
who stopped the war of his retreat. And
he even said that even 100 years
[music]
ago people were teaching meditation
wrong, saying think about
nothing. And this is in this book, this is the devil saying that.
And this is a very important
thing when you put this
picture together. This is not a very good
yoga class. By the way, the asanas are very good, the yoga is
very
good, the meditation before the asanas is not very
good, but these Yuji teachers are very
good, that's why I still
go to these Yuji classes. They give
you these headphones when they start to
put in
meditation. I put in my
earplugs so that I can't hear them. But when
they talk about yoga, I just
listen, I follow the instructions. This is an old
problem, that when they think that
meditation is thinking about nothing. So in the
tantric sense of the diamond
path, the goal  The diamond path is to reach
the goal before the one who died. And you don't
think about
it. Who's going to die first, who's going to die
last. We don't know, we don't think about
it.
It's
usually, well, a mess. And we don't
know who's going to be who, who's going to
be next. And that's the reality of this
diamond path system. You're
trying to reach the goal before
you
die. It's a run, it's a
marathon, it's a race.
And someone will say, "Remember that woman?"
Well, she's gone, unfortunately. She had a
car accident and it's a
race. And then everyone's sorry, and then everyone's
thinking, what's going to happen to lunch, and we're all in the
diamond path race.
So,
you see, I've been putting bits of the
diamond path into everything I've
been saying. This race is the point of the diamond
path. The reason the diamond path is the
most important idea. Reach it, and
then
relax. If you don't die, if you're
not dying yet, that's good.
I
know what's going to happen.  with me when I die, where
I am, where I will be. The teachers are waiting for
me. I have everything already arranged. And you
have to worry about it when you
can. You have to worry about it. And
this is the diamond path, the focus on one life.
This person who teaches you and says,
"Meditate on nothing, it's actually
killing you." This is not just a
joke. They have to go to the
Samadhi house, to the Samadhi
meditation house. Yes, to
me it's not 10 minutes before class. It's not this
irreplaceable time that you're
losing in this
meditation. I'm going to sell the company to
Raven
Buffett. He had 81 million, and now
he has 43 trillion.
He's 9094 now. I don't even know.
If he has 143 trillion, he can
buy a few hours from
someone for 100 million a
day. I don't care what you're
worth. I'll take a piece of your life.
But you  you can't do it, even
when you have so much money. And the person who
teaches terrible meditation, he
kills you. He steals your time, the most valuable thing
you have. It's a
tragedy. It's worse than if
you had anything. It's a tragedy. And this is if
you had diarrhea right now and this happened to you
. There, for example, the wretch
was diarrhea and it's not a joke. This is serious. It's the
same as if you lost 10 minutes before
yoga. And the point is that no one will give you
back this time, these 10
minutes. It would
probably be better to cut your
hand, because you can bandage it, it
can, it will recover, well, it will heal, it will recover.
And this is a serious debate, actually, because
he kills people, not their
hearts. He teaches them the right meditation -
this is a tragedy. It's like someone dying
in a
plane crash, but a car
crash.
This is the
devil talking about how quickly
the system works. They will lead to the results of
meditation that do not exist in this life,
not in the next life. They will achieve a
result that does not exist in this
life or the next. they will achieve a
state of restlessness. They
can do nothing for a while.
They will achieve a result. So what is this about
? Who is talking about this? Who is talking about this
? Yes, the diamond path is the
fastest way, but it still takes a
long time. If someone
promises you quick liberation, let me
tell you an idea from wisdom, like an old
man with experience. This is what happened
to me. Someone was sitting next to me on the plane
. I would like to know the secrets of
this market. You need to invest.
[music]
They have a special chip. You need to
invest in a company like MDA. You will
make money right away
. And the founder of Sony Corporation, what is
his, what is his name, what was his name
? Yeah.
Mostorito. And what he
said. This is a cool book. What is the name of
this book?
Yes, it was made in  Japan. It's called
Made in Japan. I love this book.
I'll also tell you something. If someone knows
what stock is going to go up or
down. Do you think they're really going to
tell you that? The logic is just ironclad.
If someone knows
100% that your stock is going to go up,
why would they tell you that
? They're just investing their
money. And he
laughed. I don't play with these
stocks. That's what the founder of
Sony Corporation said. I don't buy
stocks. It's like a casino.
It's the same thing. Nobody can
tell you what's going to happen tomorrow, what's going to happen
the day after tomorrow. You
could say if they did, they would
n't be experts. They wouldn't make
this much money. So why am I
telling you this? So this person promises,
"You
can't do it." Think about it.
Listen, I'm a craftsman. I have a certain
hat. I can say,
"Wow, look at this thing, look at
my work.  I have this tool.  This
confirms that I am a master of mantras.  I
have statues, I have
ding-ding-ding-ding-ding-ding, that's
all.  And I have students with all these tools.
I can lead you to
enlightenment in three days.  This is the crinocactus
I was just talking about.  You can do
your ding-ding, but I need to get back
to my work, to my lesson.
Do you understand what I'm talking about?  This is the
hat they wear, it won't
lead you to Buddhahood.
So a promise you can't keep
that you can make very
quickly.  It will be difficult, it
will be a difficult job.  You will need to
sit on
your butt.  You will have many
bad days and many difficult
times, then you will definitely reach your
goal.  The Diamond Path is not a
piece of chocolate or candy.  This
means I have to shut up
already.  I like this next
poem.
This moro means in English it
means
some kind of stupid person.  Well,
fool.  And he accuses
this
and accuses the angel of understanding
wisdom, uh, understanding the pen.  And he
says, "You're just an
idiot."  And he: "Why do you say that? An
angel doesn't really get upset.
He says: "Devil, I can do
incredible things, and you're just a nice
lady there.  You are such an
idiot!  In English, they say: "You're
so stupid you can't tie your own
shoelaces."  You have never seen
these words.
This is a 16th
century Utsang.  Yashe
means every
week means you are who you are.  He
accuses you of not being a very good person.
Who says this?
You say, he says,
you
and he accuses the Angel of being
so smart, you understand
the pen so well,
you Yes, and where are you?  Where are you?  You're
not at home all the time.
Who do you spend time with?  Why don't you always
come home?  You're so
beautiful,
so sweaty, but you never have a
home.  What does this
mean?  So I wonder what this
[music]
means.  Really understand the pen once a
month.
He accuses
her
of being a bad lady, a bad
wife, because he has to live with her in
her
mind.  The mind of the devil must live in
the mind of
one person next to this, this beautiful
lady, with this
angel.  She's like: "Who is this comrade?
Where did he come from anyway? What? What are you
doing here? Why are you never here? And that's what
he says. And that
means, because people think about Lutska
once a week. All the rest of the time they
complain about
others. He has no idea what a bad
person he is, once a month. Yeah. It
comes from me. That's what I do.
She's just not home often. Do you understand
what this is about? You should laugh, because you
understand it.
I think it's cool. He accuses
Zizi. That she cheats on her
husband? That's nonsense. They live
together. Well, he doesn't
see her. She's never
home. It's actually really cool. A
very, very deep
metaphor. We mention the pen very
rarely.
You have to make a beautiful picture for
this poem. Do you understand
how much time we have left?
A few minutes. Okay.
Let's do the next poem. The
spelling here is a little wrong. Those,  who hopes to create
good
karma. Who says that?
We can
call Buddha for two
minutes. I don't understand why the whole world doesn't
fall at my feet. If they do my
meditation, they
will come to the future in a few days.
Yes, if we if you really want to
get good karma, by the way,
they
try to direct you not to
forgive, not to pay, for example,
taxes. So, in Buddhism, the devil
asks, he convinces that the pen comes
from his own side.
But if he makes you believe that the
pen does not come by itself, that is,
if the pen comes by itself, then he is
successful. If he managed to do that,
then you have become his slaves. You
will blame people all your
life. You
must be jealous of me. Because I am
so strong and you are so
weak. Who says that? The devil. Is that
true? Well, it's not that he is
weak.
She beats him so well every time she is at home
. If  you will think about it, you
will be patient with other people. But
if you don't remember, then you are weak.
You see, she is
stronger, but if
she is never at home here, in our
mind, then she has no opportunity
to show her strength. You see what I mean?
You have to
learn. This is Michael's old way, you are
like this, if you fall asleep, show it by
shaking your head like this.
This is the third level of our skills, and the
next level is to sleep with your
eyes open. Just sit up straight, at least don't
fall, by the way, with your eyes open.
So now you are so
tired, you are
not You are so tired of arguing with me
. So what, is it difficult for you
to come home like this?
Why? Well, then don't come home at all.
Forget altogether where this person
came from. We have already decided that the person
who brings me pain, she comes
from you. I don't need to
remember this in Buddhism. This is such a
fight with some, but a schizophrenic. What is this
like this? Oh, you hurt me. Oh, you
told me something. Oh, you're my It
comes from me. No, it can't
come from me.
No-no, it would be much easier. And if you
came
Buddhism caused you Vilja. You're such a
product. Yes, you're stupid. Of course, it would be
easier that way. Or than all this struggle, this
Buddhism, that it all comes from me. No.
No, no
. He's like: "Why do
n't you come home?" That's it, don't
come home, leave this house. Those are his
last words. So the beautiful woman, this
angel, she appears
again. The beautiful woman is wisdom. She
comes home. Hello, dear, I'm
home.
She raises the pen, she uses
it in her life. Some people understand the
pen, but don't use it in their
life, and some people
use this
understanding.
Hey, we have one minute left.
Hold on, hold on, don't fall asleep.
When I was sitting in the Geshe course in the camp,  in the
refugee camp, when it was
45° heat, the heat was there and the rain was pouring down
from the roof all over me. I made
a promise, I promised in the future, when
I will be a
teacher, I will make them suffer.
This became my dream. And this became my
dream. And I really dream about it. This was the
thought
I had. You don't have the navigability. You don't have
any good quality. You have
the illusion that you are a good
meditation master. Not only you.
You don't have any great qualities.
You don't even have the
tools to create these qualities. That
means that
you don't know how to
meditate. You think that thinking about
nothing is good meditation, because you will
never become a good person,
because you don't have the skills, you don't have the
tools. You think because you
think that you are sitting in inditation, not
thinking about anything.
Everything is fine.